

PROFILE

I am a recent graduate from the University of California, San Diego, majoring in Nanoengineering, with a focus in Material Science. I will commence my Graduate studies in the Fall of 2020 as a Master's student at UCSD.

My experiences as a tutor and as a member of various clubs have formed my desire to venture both into research and teaching.

Currently, I am working to further expand my knowledge in the areas of fabrication and characterization of nanomaterials, and development of new techniques to facilitate their production in Dr. Shirley Meng's Laboratory for Energy Storage and Conversion (LESC) at UCSD.

Attended Architecture school in Mexico for three years before moving to the U.S. and switching majors.

CONTACT

PHONE: (619) 206-1235

EMAIL:

<u>Aethencam99@gmail.com</u> (Personal) <u>Cam077@ucsd.edu</u> (University)

SKILLS

Fluent in English and Spanish.

Proficient in Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint.

Experience with MatLab, Origin, Crystalmaker, AutoCad, Photoshop, SketchUp, and limited SolidWorks experience.

CARLOS MEJIA

B. S. IN NANOENGINEERING

EDUCATION

University of California, San Diego

Master of Science in Nanoengineering Starting Sep. 2020

Bachelor of Science in Nanoengineering

Sep. 2017 - June 2020

GPA: 3.86; Graduated Cum Laude; Provost's Honors: Winter '18 – Spring '20; Courses included Crystallography, Material Science & Engineering, and Quantum Mechanics.

Grossmont College

Aug. 2014 - June 2017

GPA: 3.88; Graduated with Honors, receiving an Associate's Degree in University Studies: Mathematics, Natural Science, and Computer Science.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Laboratory for Energy Storage and Conversion – Research Assistant

Feb. 2019-Present

Assisting one of the group's Graduate Students with her work on synthesis of cathode materials for lithium-ion batteries. Tasks include synthesis of nano-powders, fabrication of electrodes, and assembly & testing of coin cells, as well as characterization through X-ray diffraction and SEM.

Grossmont College - Math Tutor

Sep. 2015-June 2017

Worked one-on-one with community college students to discuss and work through math problems and concepts. Occasionally, would lead small workshops and study sessions (10-15 students). Courses I tutored included Algebra, Geometry, Trigonometry, Calculus, and Differential Equations.

Food Industry - Sushi Chef

Dec. 2013-Sep. 2019

Worked part-time in various restaurants in San Diego County as a Sushi Chef. Tasks included preparation of the food and other ingredients on a day-to-day basis, customer service, inventory tracking, and floor management.

ACTIVITIES

Worked as staff for a FIRST Lego League robotics competition at Grossmont College.

Helped organize field trips to the California Science Center and the Griffith Observatory for the Science Club at Grossmont College.

Hosted elementary school students at our community college and performed live chemistry experiment demos for them as part of the Science Club.

Helped arrange networking events for community college students, as well as fundraisers, parties, and events on-campus as a member of the Honor's Club and in association with other student-run clubs.